hi it's Nick said love from the label machine here
and on today's podcast
we have Harry Sonnet from Daily playlist.com
Harry deep dived into the world of Spotify playlisting
the importance of curators and playlisting
and how and when
you should start submitting your music for playlists
during a release cycle
we also discussed how
and when to market your own playlist as a record label
and he shared his views on how to spend $500
on marketing your next single
if you're interested in all
and how Spotify playlisting works
to further your label or artist revenues
you are gonna love this episode
you're listening to the Label Machine series
a podcast to inspire and help indie record labels
and artists to build income streams for their music
I'm Nick Sadler
a music entrepreneur that has helped star
and run multiple indie record labels
in this series
I'll be speaking with music industry leaders
about their experience and the lessons they learn
on how they both market and grow their music income
welcome to the Label Machine series
where we discuss with our guests how artists
and record labels promote and monetize music
today's guest is Harry Sodnick
Harry is an accomplished product lead
currently based in Berlin Germany
during his tenor at 5 Victors Inc
he helped transform daily playlist.com into a thriving
curator centric platform
growing up from 15,000 to 40,000 monthly active users
he also spearheaded the Republic at
groundbreaking with 3 project on the polygon blockchain
as a creative manager
he crafted audiovisual assets
for gaming and music products
collaborating with renowned esports partners
such as league of Legends
Fortnite and Rocket League
diverse background of the music industry
and freelance consulting
Harry brings a wealth of knowledge to the table
which I am looking forward to sharing with you today
Harry how are you
yeah uh thank you for the intro
yeah I'm doing really well
um summer in Berlin so far has been a lot of rain
um which is currently stopped for a little bit
maybe I see a bit of sunlight but um
apart from that
all good thanks
mate awesome
so you were born and now you're here talking to me
tell me what happened in between
so originally
I was born in the Midlands in the UK
moved up to the North East of England
got to mention that
hence the accent
yeah I'm very big part of my personality
um and then from there
I started learning to play drums when I was about ten
and instantly threw myself into playing with bands
like with my friends
which really sparked um
I love for music
specifically live music at the time
playing in bands and just generally um
I guess listen to all different types of genres
whatever it may be
um this sort of was a complete
a constant throughout my
like adolescence
like my teen years
just playing music
being surrounded by musical people
um which kinda translated to again
playing in lots of different types of bands
um and then eventually making the move to uh
Brighton um
from there um
I was studying music business
um bin and I was also against still playing a bands
and at the time um
one of my bands they
we got picked up by some fairly reputable managers
which is really cool
because I was learning about the music industry
before that
I had a very DIY approach
but then I was working with the team and
you know really getting to apply
um what I was learning um
so some really cool like uh
opportunities came out from that um
we played out in like Glastonbury
South Korea
uh reading the Leeds Festival
and really got to see some like um
the inside of the music industry that you
getting taught about
um you know
on like paper
and so from there
ended up graduating
the band kinda dissolved very naturally
um and then yeah
sorry job opportunity over here in Berlin
working for a gaming music company
5 vectors um
who had daily playlist under their repertoire
of their products
um that they're working on um
and from there yeah
really made the jump
um my other side to me
as well as being um
really into my like punk
garage rock music
first and foremost
is I'm a massive nerd
absolutely massive nerd so um
working within a space where it was a crossover
between gaming and music
and esports and all of this coming together
it seemed like a bit of a too good to be true situation
especially with
the opportunity to move out here to Berlin um
so yeah from there
I started working on daily playlist
like back in like 2019
um with the original founder um
but also working across the host of projects which um
you mentioned there
and yeah what was it
like 2023 now
and then yeah
sort of now only working on daily playlists um
but yeah it was um
along the way picked up a whole host of um
experiences working across different technologies
I'm working with different types of music campaigns
looking at it from like the tech angle
but also still
looking at it from the independent artist angle
the label angle and uh
really keeping the post on what is going on within
the music industry
so get in for me
I guess the perfect like 3
60 view of um
my little space
that's it oh
it's amazing
and and you know
that's what so many of our listeners
especially are in that
that independent music space
but you know
combined with the business
and technology aspects as well
so um jumping into Daily Playlist as well
which is one of the reasons why I reached out to you uh
it's one of the few playlist companies we recommend
at The Label Machine
it's very popular
are you guys
do a great job over there
can you give us a
quick rundown of what Daily Playlists is at its essence
and a rundown of
what are your main activities are there
mm hmm so in it's car essence
Daily Playlist is a very simple and easy to use
a playlist submission platform um
we really automate the play uh
the process
so artists can go through a flow of entering the song
just searching for it
connecting to the platform via the Spotify uh
Spotify login
and then having uh
been able to select from over 18,000 playlists
to submit to
or over 400 premium curators
which I can get into a bit later um
for the curator inside the things we again
really pride ourselves in simplifying and automating
the processes where
the curators can organise
can fill the through submissions um
and can easily find the right music for their playlist
while also um
having a platform which allows them to grow
and monetize um
their brands and profiles
hmm so what
how does the
cause I believe if you got a free account
you can get 20 credits and is
is that essentially 20
submissions
is that right
yeah exactly
so that's a very much like a 1 to 1
um yeah value
okay so I I
I've submitted my
my music what's the
what I mean
what's the I mean
70 people love daily playlist
cause you can submit to 20 playlists for free
what's the uh
how does the business model work
like how do you
you know how does the company
sort of make money if there's no financial
movement round it
so we do have two different monetization layers
so one of these is our Artist Pro
um layer which is a subscription plan
which you can get for 1499 per month
or hundred and fifty dollars per year
um which basically gives you tools
which allow you to make the most
of daily playlist
really expand on um
your experience
on the site
so um we can get into the individual products um
on a deeper level in a bit
but we have a tool which automates
automatically submits to playlist for you
um which we have a algorithm which you built
which can basically
match your submission to the playlist
um based on the playlist
like quality
um we also have the ability to add uh
pre saves to what we called the gate system
um which means that if you have a playlist
or if you wanna create a contest
you can then have the terms and conditions of the
entry or submission
to being pre saving the release
um and then also we um
have a number of other features
which include like uh
our trending list
our track Explorer
and very community based
engagement um
is because we have a very
very active community
which is super
um open but then on the other side
we have the premium layer for curators
in which we have a very
heavily vetted um
marketplace of curators who have got um
proven engagement
genuine um quality to the curation
and their branding
especially is what we look at
and just very much
established within the space
so for $2 per submission
you can submit to these curators
when we split that 60
40 in the curators favour
per submission that they review
ah gotchain
so can people just submit anytime to those
premium playlists
would you have to be on the membership model
for that to work
so anyone can buy
so we have two different um
credit types
we have the standard credits
which are the ones that you get every week to 20
that refresh on a Monday um
and then we also have the premium credits um
which you can purchase
I think for 20
um it is 39
99 and for 10 it's 1999 um
and then you can freely spend those premium credits to
the premium curators
so rather than submitting to an individual playlist
you submit to a curator
who then evaluates and gives you feedback on the um
on your submission and um
if it's a fit for their profile
they'll select which playlist and position
they wanna add you to
and whereas
I guess the difference from that to the standard
submissions is that on the standard side
you submit directly to a playlist
interesting yeah
so are you seeing then a trend
of when you talk about a curator is a
is a curator
like someone who manages
a bunch of playlists
essentially
in this case
yeah so curators
you know the world of music curation is huge
you haven't uh
channels such as like colours
um circle and those muscle
like even by boiling right there
like music curation in a
in a sense yeah
then you have
in our essence
you working with the playlisters who have um
assets which are the playlist
which they spend a lot of time mastering the growth
mastering the curation aspects and that branding
um and yeah
so that's that's how we
when I refer to curators on
in this case
I'm talking about like the playlist is
um so yeah gotcha
and when you're saying
is why you're submitting to the curators the
the premium and
and you'd get
they would review it
and see which playlist they would add it to
are you getting is this
is the artist submitting or whatever submitting
getting actual feedback from like
you know like
I guess the quality of the song or the style
or you know
are they getting that kind of constructive feedback
or is it more just yeah
we think we can work for it or no
we can't what
what sort of depth does it go to
so in the current setup
if a curator accepts the song
they don't necessarily have to leave a comment